Guide to the Mike Frost graphic designer collection of Houston Hip-Hop artwork, 1999-2009 MS 682
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Mike Frost graphic designer collection of Houston Hip-Hop artwork
1999-2009
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Frost, Mike
MS 682
2 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Examples of graphic design work done by Mike Frost for hip-hop artists in the Houston area.
Biographical / Historical
With over 15 years experience as both a Graphic Designer and Photographer, Mike Frost has defined the image and branding of rap/hip-hop albums in Texas an arguably the South. He started out designing event fliers in the Punk and electronic music communities of Houston in the mid 90s. Shortly after learning one of the first releases of Adobe's Photoshop, many of his friends started pursuing their music careers. Most notable were; Mike Jones, Chamillionaire, Paul Wall, Devin the Dude, Slim Thug, Z-Ro, and Trae. With Mike, Cham, and Paul certifying platinum and Cham's Grammy, Frost's position as the go to man for graphic design, web development, and photography was solidified. He is currently Creative Director for Swisha House and his own boutique creative agency, SLFEMP. He created SLFEMP as a means to bring multifaceted and talented artists together to collaborate on album packaging, press, commercial, web development, and fine-art projects. His most recent Credits include: Slim Thug The Boss of all Bosses, Paul Wall The Fast Life, and photography and design for Microsoft's Zune advertisements featuring Common. (excerpted from SLFEMP "About" page Facebook, https://www.facebook.com/pg/SLFEMP713/about/, accessed March 17, 2017)
See online video on Mike Frost's career path in graphic design, at https://youtu.be/dL1urXoHvvU. Guest appearances are: G Dash, ESG, Slim Thug, Mike Frost, Brandon Holley.
Content Description
Examples of graphic design work done by Mike Frost for hip-hop artists in the Houston area.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mike Frost, 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects
Art; Artists; Rap (Music); Performing arts; Music
Document Types
posters; T-shirts
Places
Texas
Subjects (Persons)
Frost, Mike
- Series I: T-shirts
  - 1 Paul Wall East Life t-shirt, green cotton with white lettering (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Magazines, 2003-2007
  - Envy magazine / Houston life, March #26 featuring Paul Wall on cover (year unclear) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rap Illustrated V.4 2004 featuring Z-RO on the cover (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rap Illustrated V.2 2003 featuring TRAE of the G-Maab on cover (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hustlenomics 3rd edition 2007 featuring SwishaHouse artists on the cover (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ozone Magazine 3rd annual Ozone Awards (date?) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Texas Music Winter 2006 Issue 25 featuring Mike Jones on the cover (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Houston Press issue - Slim Thug on cover, April 2-8, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Houston Press issue - Pimp C on cover Dec 13-19, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series III: Flyers, flats and one-sheets
  - Two 8.5x11" one sheets (Lone Star Ridaz) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 2 one sheets for distributors (Baby Beesh: On Tha Cool; and Twin Beredaz) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Thirteen small flyers, including 2 microphone shaped SwishaHouse All Freestyles 4; Yuckmouth; Kickdoor Bandits; Z-RO; Kamakazeez; SwishaHouse Christmas Festival; Mista Da Masta; Big Tiger of da Swishahouse; SK Comin' All Day (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Five 12x12" flats: Something to Lean To; On tha Cool; Lil O; Sir Daily and Doodie; Z-RO (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 6" x 18" Guerilla Maab = Res - Ur - Rect - Ed, featuring Dougie D, Trae and Z-RO; KMJ Records (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Posters
  - Poster: PSK-12 & Michael "5000" Watts - Something to Lean To - Chopped and Skrewed - Nightshift Muzik, Houston, TX (Box 2)
  - Poster: Michael Watts & Lil Mario presents - Lil Mario's Street Fame - Swisha House Records (Box 2)
  - Poster: Dope House Records / South Park Mexican - Reveille Park - Houston, TX (Box 2)
  - Poster: Screwston Vol. III - Stuck in Da Mud - Dope House Records - Houston, TX (Box 2)
  - Poster: Big Pic of Da Swishahouse - Certified (Box 2)
  - Fat Texas Records presents Texas Made: featuring Big Tee, 3-2 The Governor, J-Duce, Tony Montana, Lil' Sen "Gotti", Relentless Mafia, Villian Keys, Icey Hott & KB the Kidnappa (Box 2)
  - Poster: Lil' O - Food on tha Table; Game Face Ent. Houston, TX (Box 2)
  - Poster: 20-2-Life, Featuring C-Loc, Boo, PSK-13, Lil Keke, Mista Madd, Point Blank, The Cellmates / Inmate Records (Box 2)
  - Poster: Klas' One - The One and Only / Mixed chopped and screwed by Swisha House Michael "5000" Watts, Featuring Slim Thug, Papareu, Kamakazeez, Boonie Locc, Lil Mario, J-Dawg, A.D., 50-50, Doodie, Ghost Lansky, Agonylife, Yung Skrilla (Box 2)
  - Poster: Michael Watts Presents Mista Da Masta, Chooped Up Remix, Archie Lee of da Swishahouse (Box 2)
  - Poster: Lone Star Ridaz - 40 Days 40 nights (Box 2)
  - Poster: I-45 - Lost Between the Lines, Fuzzgun Records, 2000 ( 2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Poster: Z-RO, ca. 2004 (Box 2)
  - Poster: double sided featuring Juan Gotti / No Set Trippin; Baby Beesh On Tha Cool; Twin Beredaz (Box 2)
  - Poster: SwishaHouse All Freestyles 4, featuring Michael Watts, Chamillionaire, Sabwarfare, Lester Roy, Blyndcyde, Slim Thug, Lil Mario, Bag Tiger, Al Bolden, Paul Wall, Lil Ron, J-Dawg, Big Pic, Lil Flip, 50/50, Ron C., A.D. (Box 2)
  - Poster: Freestyles Mixed Screwed and Chopped, DJ Marco Polo, Syrup Factory, Vol 2, Coming Fall 2001. Featuring Dooney, Lil Keke, Big Mor of Wreckshop, Slim Thug, 3-2 of the Screwed Up, Click, Icey Hott of Street Military, .50 Cal, D-Yates, Ghetto, Bandit, K-Fiend, J-Boy, Project 8, Joker, Coliaon, Candyman, Young J, Ace, LaLa & The Syrup, Factory Click (Box 2)
  - Poster: SwishaHouse Presents Big Tiger (Box 2)
  - Poster: Sixth Annual Carmona Custom Car Show and Concert, Memorial Day Sunday, May 27, 2001, Houston TX (double-sided) (Box 2)
- Series V: Digital artwork organized by artist
  - Chamillionaire, 2003-04-23
    General
    Contains the album cover to Chamillionaire's The Mix Tape Messiah.
  - Devin the Dude, 2008-2017
    Contains photos, cover art, and sketches for Devin the Dude's albums Acoustic Levitation and Suite 420 by Mike Frost.
  - Paul Wall, 2017-2018
    Contains three different versions of the cover to Paul Wall's album Bounce Backs Over Setbacks.
  - Swishahouse, 2005-2021
    Contains various digital images by Mike Frost relating to Swishahouse.